A Guide to the George E. Palade papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA187
Rockefeller Archive Center
George E. Palade papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1951-1972
Rockefeller Archive Center
Tartakoff, Alan Michael
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
Palade, G. E.
FA187
4.6 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
George Emil Palade (1912-1977), a cell biologist, was affiliated with RIMR (from 1946) as a visiting investigator and later as a professor of cell biology. Professor Palade was a recipient of the Albert Lasker Basic Research Award (1966), the Horowitz Prize (1970) and the Nobel Prize (1974).
Alan Tartakoff was a member of Palade's laboratory from 1967 to 1972. His laboratory notebooks were added to Palade's collection as a representative sample of the kind of work being done in the laboratory.
Scope and Contents note
Includes correspondence and laboratory notebooks of Alan Tartakoff; dated and labeled glass slides from Palade's laboratory; and lecture notes and memoranda related to two courses on cell biology organized by George Palade at the Rockefeller University for which guest lecturers were invited.
Correspondents include Allen E. Blaurock, Britton Chance, J. B. Chappell, and Efraim Racker.
Arrangement note
Arranged by subject, then in chronological order.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 P171
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access note
Limited access. Consult archivist for assistance.
Biology -- Research; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biochemistry; Physiology; Life sciences; Medical education; Medical research; Medical sciences; Tartakoff, Alan Michael; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University; Palade, G. E.
- Cell Biology Course on Mitochondria, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Course on Biological Membranes, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alan Tartakoff Laboratory Notebooks, 1967-1971
  - 1967 March-May (Box 2, Folder I)
  - 1967 May-August (Box 2, Folder II)
  - 1967 September-November (Box 2, Folder III)
  - 1967 December-1968 May (Box 2, Folder IV)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes photos.
  - 1968 May-November (Box 2, Folder V)
  - 1968 November-1969 February (Box 2, Folder VI)
  - 1969 February-May (Box 2, Folder VII)
  - 1969 May-September (Box 2, Folder VIII)
  - 1969 October-December (Box 2, Folder IX)
  - 1970 January-February (Box 2, Folder X)
  - 1970 April (Box 2)
    Scope and Contents
  - 1970 July-October (Box 2, Folder XIII)
  - 1970 December-1971 January (Box 2, Folder XV)
  - 1971 January-February (Box 2, Folder XVI)
  - 1971 March-April (Box 2, Folder XVII)
  - 1971 April-August, (black binder) (Box 2, Folder XVIII)
- Alan Tartakoff Laboratory Notebooks, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Brookhaven Experiments & Photos, 1971 September-October (Box 3)
  - 1971 December-1972 January (Box 3, Folder XIX)
  - 1972 February (Box 3, Folder XX)
- Glass Slides
  - 1951-1952 (Box 4)
  - 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 6)